Napoleon paced to and fro in silence, occasionally snuffing at the ground.
His tail had grown rigid and twitched sharply from side to side, a sign in him
of intense mental activity.
Suddenly he halted as though his mind were made up.
>> Comrades, do you know who is responsible for this? Do you know the enemy who has
come in the night and overthrown our windmill?
Snowball!
>> He suddenly roared in a voice of thunder.
>> Snowball has done this thing in sheer malignity, thinking to set back our
plans and avenge himself for his ignominious expulsion. This traitor has
crept here under cover of night and destroyed our work of nearly a year.
Comrades, here and now I pronounce the death sentence upon Snowball, animal
hero second class, and half a bushel of apples to any animal who brings him to
justice. A full bushel to anyone who captures him alive.
>> The animals were shocked beyond measure to learn that even Snowball could be
guilty of such an action.
There was a cry of indignation and everyone began thinking out ways of
catching Snowball if he should ever come back.
Almost immediately the footprints of a pig were discovered in the grass at a
little distance from the knoll.
They could only be traced for a few yards, but appeared to lead to a hole in
the hedge.
Napoleon sniffed deeply at them and pronounced them to be Snowball's.
He gave it as his opinion that Snowball had probably come from the direction of Foxwood Farm.
>> No more delays, comrades.
>> cried Napoleon when the footprints had been examined.
>> There is work to be done. This very morning we begin rebuilding the windmill
and we will build all through the winter, rain or shine. We will teach
this miserable traitor that he cannot undo our work so easily. Remember,
comrades, there must be no alteration in